How much sun power does Costa Rica have?
I could find no information on how many
sun hours Costa Rica has online, so
we're going to find out with a real
world test. First of all, what is a sun
hour? It's an hour in the day when the
sun is at peak intensity and direction
to be captured by solar panels. As you
can see, all of my batteries are at 53%
and we are charging around 400 volts on
circuit two and around 390 on circuit
one. Let me explain why they're
different voltages. Coming up in the
tower, you can see the sun rising in the
east. That explains why circuit two has
more voltage cuz the panels are facing
the rising sun. Circuit one is still
receiving sunlight but at a worse angle
given the direction of the sun right
now. I have my circuits divided like
that. That way when the sun is rising in
the east, this one will get maximum
sunlight and then after midday when it's
going that way, that side will get
maximum sunlight. You always want to
group panels with the same direction
towards the sun together. That way when
this one is receiving maximum sunlight
and that one is shaded, the shaded
portions of that side will not reduce
the voltage of the entire circuit. Now,
let's do some math. Since I have 12,500
watts of solar up there and around 30 kW
of battery to charge, I think this
system should be fully charged by 1:00.
I do not know if my redneck
arithmetizing is correct or not, but we
will post another video in a little
while so you can know how much power
from the sun you can get on day one.